Guide to the Gerald H. Anderson Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Writings, Lectures, Research Files, 1957-2012; Series II
  - Research files
    - Christianity in the Philippines, 1939, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Jewish-Christian relations, 1972-1985 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Jewish-Christian relations, 1977-1978 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Jewish-Christian relations, 1977-1983 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Jewish-Christian relations, 1983, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Jewish-Christian relations, 1980-1986 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Jewish-Christian relations, 1976-1985 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Jewish-Christian relations, 1976-1977, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Jonestown cult, 1978 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Methodist mission study, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Missions archives and libraries, 1963, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Missions history and leaders, 1952-2009 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Mormon missions, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Peter Parker - articles and talks by GA, 2003-2013 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Peter Parker - notes and correspondence, 1979-2007 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Peter Parker - photocopies of primary source materials, 1855-1896 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Peter Parker - secondary sources, 1955-2006 (Box 51, Folder 4-5)
    - Peter Parker - photographs, no date (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Peter Parker - bibliographies, no date (Box 51, Folder 7)
- Conference and Consultation Activities, 1959-2008; Series III
  - International Association for Mission Studies
    - Dreibergen conference, 1972 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - San Jose conference, 1976 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Executive Committee meeting, Aberdeen, 1979 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Working Party on Mission Studies and Information Management, Rome, 1980 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Africa trip, 1983 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Harare conference, 1985 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Rome conference, 1988 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Hawaii conference, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Buenos Aires conference, 1996 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Hammanskraal conference, 2000 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - "Rescuing the Memory of Our Peoples" - Joint IACM-IAMS Archives and Documentation Conference, Rome, 2002 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Port Dickson, Malaysia conference, 2004 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Balatonfüred, Hungary conference, 2008 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - International Missionary Council / World Council of Churches Commission on World Mission and Evangelism
    - "The Christian World Mission in the Ecumenical Age" consultation at Seabury House, 1959 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - "The Christian World Mission in the Ecumenical Age" consultation - background material, 1956-1959 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Documentation re. Missionary Task of the Church, 1961-1962 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Conference on World Mission and Evangelism, Melbourne, 1980 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Conference on World Mission and Evangelism, Melbourne, 1980 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Conference on World Mission and Evangelism, Melbourne, 1980 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - CWME Executive Committee meeting at OMSC, 1982 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - 50th anniversary of IMC Tambaram meeting, 1988 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - 50th anniversary of IMC Tambaram meeting, 1988 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - World Conference on Mission and Evangelism, San Antonio, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - World Conference on Mission and Evangelism, San Antonio, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Conference on World Mission and Evangelism, Salvador, Bahia, Brazil, 1996 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Conference on World Mission and Evangelism, Salvador, Bahia, Brazil, 1996 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - World Council of Churches Consultation on the Church and the Jewish People
    - London meeting and follow-up re. Guidelines for Jewish Christian Dialogue, 1981 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Arnoldshain, Germany meeting, 1986 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Sigtuna, Sweden meeting, 1988 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Geneva meeting, 1992 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Budapest meeting, 1994 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - World Council of Churches Ecumenical Institute
    - Bossey consultation on African and Asian contributions of contemporary theology, 1976 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Kennedy Institute Jewish-Christian-MuslimTrialogue
    See also background material in Series IV, Subject Files / Collected Material
    - Washington, D.C. meetings, 1979 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Washington, D.C. meetings, 1979, 1980 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Washington, D.C. meetings, 1980, 1981 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Washington, D.C. meetings, 1982 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Washington, D.C. meetings, 1982-1983 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Washington, D.C. meetings, 1984 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Consultation on World Evangelization, Pattaya, Thailand (Lausanne Committee for World Evangelization), 1980 Jun
    - Newsletters and papers, 1979-1980 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, program, 1979-1980 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - "Reaching the Jews" working group, 1979-1980 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Reactions to conference, 1980 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Lausanne CommitteeTask Force on Jewish Evangelism, Newmarket, England, 1983
    - Program and papers, 1983 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence and background material, 1983 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Lausanne Consultation on Jewish Evangelism, Chicago
    - Papers, 1987 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Sino-Nordic Conference on Chinese Contextual Theology, Finland, 2003
    - Program and papers, 2003 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - GHA response paper and background materials, 2003 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Background materials, 2003 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Other conferences and events
    - Oxford Institute of Methodist Theological Studies, Oxford, UK, 1958 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Presidents Institute, Miami, FL, 1971 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - IDOC Seminar on the Future of the Missionary Enterprise, OMSC, Ventnor, NJ, 1974 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - American Society of Missiology conference: "World Evangelization Today: Convergence or Divergence?", 1980 Aug (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Haystack Prayer Meeting 175th anniversary, Andover Newton Theological School, 1981 Oct (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - India trip, 1981 Dec - 1982 Jan (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Inter-Church Consultation on Future Trends in Christian World Mission, Maryknoll, NY, 1985 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Ecumenical Mission Consultation, Madison, CT, 1987 (Box 46, Folder 5)
      Ecumenical Mission Consultation co-sponsored by U.S. Catholic Mission Association and the Division of Overseas Ministries of the NCCCUSA
    - National Workshop on Christian-Jewish Relations, Stamford, CT, 1996 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - United Methodists and Jews: Colloquium, Boston, 1996 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - U.S. Catholic Mission Congress, 2000 (Box 46, Folder 8)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1952-2004; Series IV
  - Biographical documentation
    - Biographical statements from Boston University School of Theology Alumni Magazine and from Festschrift for Anderson, 1966, 1993 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Programs, clippings, listings as Methodist clergy, Erie Conference, exam booklet, 1952-1959 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Documentation re. receiving Ph.D. from Boston University, appointment and travel to Union Theological Seminary, Philippines, including passports, 1960 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Documentation from period teaching at Union Theological Seminary, Philippines, 1961-1962 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Incl. re. appointment as academic dean at UTS, teaching and speaking activities, 1963-1965 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Documentation of period of service at UTS, Philippines, 1966-1970 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Two scrapbooks containing memorabilia and photographs from period of service in Philippines, 1960-1970 (Box 48)
    - Incl. re. appointment as President of Scarritt College for Christian Workers, Nashville, Alumni Merit Award from Boston University School of Theology, 1970-1971 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Incl. re. resignation from Scarritt, appointment as Senior Research Associate at Cornell University, 1972-1973 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Incl. re. teaching at Drew University Theological School, 1974-1976 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Citation from The Mission Society for United Methodists; trip itineraries, 1980s (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Award from Grove City College; reviews of Anderson Festschrift, 1994 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Incl. re. honorary doctorates from Asbury Theological Seminary and Albertus Magnus College, 2000-2001 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Artifacts
    - Philippine car license plates with slogan "Christianization's 4th Centennial", 1965 (Box 48)
    - Picture book: "The World's Children in Pictures - The Philippines", by Joanne Anderson, with copies of original photographs, 1968 (Box 48)
    - Honorary Degree of Doctor of Divinity from Moravian Theological Seminary, 1995 (Box 48)
    - Plaques commemorating Gerald Anderson, including appointment at Director Emeritus of OMSC, Mission Award from U.S. Catholic Mission Association, H.T. Maclin Award, 1952-2004 (Box 49)
    - Metal disk commemorating 50th anniversary of International Missionary Council, 1988 (Box 49)
    - Painted wooden cross; etchings of Marburg and Reformation era theologians, watercolor painting of Marburg, 1956, n.d. (Box 49)
- Audio-Visual Material, 1947-2003; Series V
  - Photographs
    - Anderson with parents, working road crew in Pennsylvania, at Bossey Ecumenical Institute, 1940s-1950s (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Primarily from time in Philippines, 1960s (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Events and conferences, 1980s-1990s (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Events and conferences, Rome and Italy trip, 1988 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Events and conferences, incl. Africa trip, 2000, 2003 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Photos gathered for IAMS history (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Movies
    - DVDs: "Anderson Family" (Part 1 and 2); "Fond Memories of the Union Theological Seminary Missionary Work in the Philippines"; "Union Theological Seminary, New Campus", 1960s (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Audio cassettes
    - "World Mission of the Church" by GHA - Thesis Theological Cassettes; Lectures and talks by GHA, 1977-1992 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - GHA lectures at All Nations Christian College, UK and Emmanuel School of Religion, 2000 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - 50th anniversary of International Missionary Council, Tambaram, 1988 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Lectures by R. Pierce Beaver at OMSC, 1978 (Box 49)
    - ISAE conference lectures: "A Century of World Evangelization", 1986 (Box 49)